<story-context id=".bmad/bmm/workflows/4-implementation/story-context/template" v="1.0">
  <metadata>
    <epicId>1</epicId>
    <storyId>1</storyId>
    <title>Initialize Frontend Application</title>
    <status>drafted</status>
    <generatedAt>2025-12-04</generatedAt>
    <generator>BMAD Story Context Workflow</generator>
    <sourceStoryPath>C:\Users\mrmag\Desktop\SKOLE\IBE160\TURNUSPARTIET\docs\sprint-artifacts/1-1-initialize-frontend-application.md</sourceStoryPath>
  </metadata>

  <story>
    <asA>developer</asA>
    <iWant>set up a new Flutter project with the standard folder structure</iWant>
    <soThat>we have a clean, consistent foundation for building the UI and client-side logic</soThat>
    <tasks>
- [ ] **Task 1: Initialize Flutter Project and Define Structure** (AC: #1, #2)
  - [ ] Run `flutter create` to generate the project scaffolding.
  - [ ] Add the new project files to version control.
  - [ ] Verify the generated project adheres to standard Flutter conventions for folder structure.
  - [ ] **Testing:** Manually inspect the created directory structure to ensure it matches community best practices.

- [ ] **Task 2: Implement Design System Foundation** (AC: #3)
  - [ ] Create a `theme.dart` file to house the application's theme data.
  - [ ] Implement the "Growth" color palette (`primary: #198754`, `secondary: #e8f5e9`, etc.) as defined in the UX spec.
  - [ ] Configure the typography settings (font family, type scale, line height) in the theme.
  - [ ] Apply the theme in `MaterialApp`.
  - [ ] **Testing:** Visually confirm the "Growth" theme and typography are correctly applied in the running application.

- [ ] **Task 3: Verify Build Targets** (AC: #4)
  - [ ] Configure a build runner for an Android emulator.
  - [ ] Configure a build runner for an iOS simulator.
  - [ ] **Testing:** Compile and launch the boilerplate app on the Android emulator and the iOS simulator, ensuring it runs without crashing.</tasks>
  </story>

  <acceptanceCriteria>
1. A new Flutter project is created in the repository.
2. The project follows the standard Flutter folder structure.
3. The "Growth" color theme and typography from the UX spec are configured.
4. The app compiles and runs on both an Android emulator and an iOS simulator.</acceptanceCriteria>

  <artifacts>
    <docs>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/prd.md</path>
        <title>Product Requirements Document</title>
        <section>Project Classification</section>
        <snippet>Based on the mobile-first approach and the focus on student learning, this project is classified as a mobile_app in the edtech domain.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/prd.md</path>
        <title>Product Requirements Document</title>
        <section>Mobile App Specific Requirements</section>
        <snippet>The application will be developed using a cross-platform framework (e.g., React Native, Flutter) to ensure simultaneous release on both iOS and Android and to facilitate a fast-follow web application.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/prd.md</path>
        <title>Product Requirements Document</title>
        <section>User Experience Principles</section>
        <snippet>The user experience must be a direct reflection of the core value proposition: reducing cognitive load. The UI should feel calm, clear, and instantly usable.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture Specification: The AI Helping Tool</title>
        <section>Technology Stack</section>
        <snippet>Frontend: Flutter. Rationale: Cross-Platform: Single codebase for iOS, Android, and Web ensures consistency and development speed. Performance: Compiles to native code for high performance. UI: Excellent integration with the chosen Material Design system.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>The AI Helping Tool UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>Design System Foundation</section>
        <snippet>Material Design was selected to ensure faster development, leverage great default components, and achieve robust cross-platform consistency across mobile (Android, iOS adaptations) and web applications.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>The AI Helping Tool UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>Color System</section>
        <snippet>Chosen Theme: Theme 2: "Growth". Strategy: Soft, natural greens paired with warm neutrals create an approachable, positive, and motivating environment. This theme evokes growth and harmony, aligning with the emotional goal of efficiency and productivity. Core Palette: Primary: #198754, Secondary: #e8f5e9, Background: #f9f9f9, Surface: #ffffff, Text: #212529, Text Secondary: #5f6368, Success: #198754, Error: #d93025, Border: #e0e0e0.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>The AI Helping Tool UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>Typography</section>
        <snippet>Leveraging our Material Design foundation, we will adopt a typography system optimized for readability and clarity. Font Family: A clean, modern sans-serif typeface (e.g., Roboto or similar) for both headings and body text, ensuring consistency and legibility across all platforms. Type Scale: Material Design's responsive type scale will be used. A base font size of 16px (1rem) is recommended for body text. Line Height: 1.5 for body text, 1.2 for headings. Font Weights: Used purposefully to differentiate information hierarchy.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>docs/ux-design-specification.md</path>
        <title>The AI Helping Tool UX Design Specification</title>
        <section>Responsive Design & Accessibility</section>
        <snippet>The application will implement a comprehensive responsive design strategy based on specific breakpoints and layout grid to ensure an optimal and adaptable user experience across all target platforms. Compliance Target: WCAG 2.1 Level AA compliance across all platforms (mobile and web).</snippet>
      </artifact>
    </docs>
    <code></code>
    <dependencies>
      <ecosystem name="Flutter">
        <framework>Flutter SDK</framework>
        <note>Specific version will be defined upon project initialization (e.g., in pubspec.yaml)</note>
      </ecosystem>
    </dependencies>
  </artifacts>

  <constraints>
    <constraint>
      <type>Framework</type>
      <description>Use Flutter for the frontend application.</description>
    </constraint>
    <constraint>
      <type>Design System</type>
      <description>The UI must adhere to Material Design. The specific theme is "Growth".</description>
    </constraint>
    <constraint>
      <type>Typography</type>
      <description>Use a clean sans-serif font (e.g., Roboto) with a base size of 16px and a line height of 1.5 for body text.</description>
    </constraint>
    <constraint>
      <type>Project Structure</type>
      <description>Adhere to standard Flutter conventions.</description>
    </constraint>
    <constraint>
      <type>Target Platforms</type>
      <description>The app must compile and run on both Android and iOS emulators/simulators.</description>
    </constraint>
  </constraints>
  <interfaces></interfaces>
  <tests>
    <standards>Testing for this story will primarily involve manual verification of project setup, visual confirmation of implemented design elements, and successful compilation and execution on target emulators/simulators. Adherence to Flutter's standard testing practices will be followed as the project evolves.</standards>
    <locations>
      <location>test/</location>
      <location>Visual Inspection (UI)</location>
      <location>Emulator/Simulator Environment</location>
    </locations>
    <ideas>
      <idea acId="1,2">Manually inspect the created Flutter project directory structure for adherence to standard conventions.</idea>
      <idea acId="3">Visually confirm the "Growth" color theme and specified typography are correctly applied in the running application on both Android and iOS.</idea>
      <idea acId="4">Compile and launch the boilerplate Flutter application on an Android emulator to ensure it runs without errors.</idea>
      <idea acId="4">Compile and launch the boilerplate Flutter application on an iOS simulator to ensure it runs without errors.</idea>
    </ideas>
  </tests>
</story-context>
